Monsters by the millions - and they're all for real!
The Swarm is a thriller, science fiction, horror film directed by Irwin Allen.
Scientist Dr.
Bradford Crane and army general Thalius Slater join forces to fight an almost invisible enemy
threatening America; killer bees that have deadly venom and attack without reason.
Disaster movie-master Irwin Allen's film contains spectacular special
effects, including a train crash caused by the eponymous swarm.
Brad Crane, played by Michael Caine.
Capt. Helena Anderson, played by Katharine Ross.
Gen. Thaddeus Slater, played by Richard Widmark.
Dr. Hubbard, played by Richard Chamberlain.
Maureen Schuester, played by Olivia de Havilland.
Felix, played by Ben Johnson.
The Swarm is a 1978 American thriller film directed and produced by Irwin
Allen and based on Arthur Herzog's 1974 novel of the same name.
It stars an ensemble cast, including Michael Caine, Katharine Ross, Richard Widmark, Richard Chamberlain, Olivia de Havilland, Ben Johnson,
Lee Grant, José Ferrer, Patty Duke, Slim Pickens, Bradford Dillman, Henry Fonda and Fred MacMurray in his final film role.
It follows a scientist and a military task force who try to prevent
a large swarm of killer bees from invading Texas.
The film received overwhelmingly negative reviews
from critics and was a box-office bomb.
Despite Paul Zastupnevich being nominated for the Academy Award for Best Costume
Design, it has since been considered one of the worst films ever made.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
insect, panic, texas, animal attack.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.